Welcome back to the JupyterLab on Gradio day, so you'll remember where we left off.
그라디오의 날 유피터랩에 잘 오셨습니다 어디까지 했는지 기억하실 거예요
We'd written two user interfaces, one of them for chatting with GPT four using the function uh, stream
두 개의 사용자 인터페이스를 작성했는데 하나는 GPT 4와 기능상 채팅용이었고 하나는
GPT, and one of them with Claude, with stream Claude.
함수용 클로드와 채팅용이었죠
Uh, and so now I put it to you.
이제 여러분께 묻죠. TUT D.
Supposing we wrote a function like this.
이런 함수를 썼다고 가정해 보죠
This function is like a composite function.
이 함수는 복합 함수예요
It's a function that calls others in that it's called stream model.
스트림 모델이라고 하는 함수로 다른 이들을 호출하죠
And it takes a prompt and it takes a model and it says if the model is GPT, then it calls stream GPT.
프롬프트와 모델을 취하고 모델이 GPT라면 스트리밍 GPT를 호출하죠
If the model is Claude, it calls stream.
클로드라면 개울이라고 하죠
Claude otherwise throws an error.
안 그러면 클로드가 실수를 하죠
So it needs to be GPT or Claude.
GPT나 클로드가 돼야 해요
And then it basically iterates through and yields each chunk in turn.
그러면 순환하면서 한 덩어리를 한 번에 수확해요
So this is in fact I called it a function, but it's not.
함수라고 불렀지만 사실은 아니죠
It's a generator.
발전기예요
Um, and it yields each chunk from one or the other models depending on which model is called.
어떤 모델로 부르느냐에 따라 다른 모델에서 덩어리가 나와요
Well, obviously that's going to work fine.
잘 작동할 거예요
That's now a function which has a few more variables.
변수가 몇 가지 더 있는 함수가 됐죠
So as far as Gradio is concerned, that's just another function.
그러니 그라디오에게 그건 또 다른 함수일 뿐이죠
And that means that we can build a user interface very easily around that function.
그 함수를 중심으로 사용자 인터페이스를 쉽게 만들 수 있다는 거죠
Let's look at it.
한번 보죠
Here it is.
여기 있네요
Here's an interface.
인터페이스예요
The function it's taking is just this this sort of hybrid generator that we just written the inputs.
이 함수는 우리가 방금 입력한 하이브리드 생성기예요
Of course we're now going to have two inputs.
물론 입력값은 2개죠
One of them is going to be your message.
그중 하나는 메시지예요
And the other of them I wish it were this easy.
다른 사람들은 이렇게 쉬우면 좋겠어요
Drop down with two values GPT or Claude label select model.
두 개의 값을 불러오는 거죠 GPT나 Clude Label SELECT 모델로요
And then, you know, have that as the output.
그런 다음 그걸 출력으로 하는 거죠
Things are rarely that easy though.
하지만 그렇게 쉬운 일은 드물죠
Oh, but this is gradio, so things really are that easy.
여긴 그라디오라서 모든 게 정말 쉬워요
Uh, sorry, I have to run this first.
죄송해요, 이것부터 확인할게요
There we go.
됐어요
It's not that easy.
그렇게 간단하지 않아요
You still do have to execute all of your code.
여전히 모든 코드를 실행해야 해요
Uh, so here we go.
자, 시작하죠
We bring it up, we say something like, how do I get from times Square to Grand Central?
Get up, 예를 들어 타임스스퀘어에서 그랜드 센트럴까지 어떻게 가죠?
and we pick one of our models.
모델 중 한 명을 선택해요
Let's pick GPT and we submit that and they're streaming back in markdown.
GPT를 선택해 제출하면 마크다운에서 스트리밍되죠
Is GPT response to that question of directions.
방향 문제에 대한 GPT의 반응이죠
Enjoy your visit again at the end.
즐거운 시간 보내세요
Very nice.
아주 좋아요
Uh, I feel like it's giving more options this time, but there we go.
이번에는 선택지가 더 많아진 것 같지만 어쩔 수 없죠
Maybe not.
아닐지도 모르죠
You'll probably remember.
기억날 거예요
Uh, I can then just flip to Claude and ask Claude the same question.
클로드를 보고 같은 질문을 하면 돼요
And here is Claude's answer to the same question.
똑같은 질문에 대한 클로드의 대답이에요
Uh, using Claude haiku.
클로드 하이쿠를 써서요
That might explain why we're getting slightly shorter, more terse answers.
그래서 대답이 짧고 간결해진 것 같아요
But, uh, isn't that amazing?
정말 놀랍지 않아요?
Isn't that cool?
멋지죠?
We just built this functionality.
이 기능성만 빌드했죠
We can flip between two different models, ask the same question, get the responses.
두 모델 사이를 넘나들면서 같은 질문을 하면 답이 나오죠 Get it
Uh, you could just have this running sometime if you wanted a nice chat UI of your own and be able
그냥 실행시킬 수도 있어요 멋진 채팅 UI를 원하시면요 다양한
to bounce it around different models.
모델로 튕길 수 있죠
Uh, it's a useful little tool.
유용한 도구죠
Um, and, uh, yeah, you can imagine an obvious exercise that I'll leave for you is to simply add
그리고 여러분이 상상할 수 있는 명백한 훈련이 하나 더 있어요 여기에 제미니를 추가하는
Gemini to the mix.
거죠
Why not?
왜요?
You can imagine.
상상이 되시죠?
It's super easy.
아주 쉬워요
You just add in.
그냥 추가하는 거죠
Gemini is another option.
제미니를 선택해도 되고요
I haven't shown you how to stream back from Gemini, but it's very similar and you can quickly google
제미니 강의에서 스트림하는 법을 보여드린 적은 없지만 아주 비슷해요 구글로 빠르게 검색하면
it to see the documentation is very clear and then add it into the mix, and then push that code so
아주 명확한 문서화가 있고 그걸 추가해서 그 코드를 푸시해 제가 갖고 다른 학생들과
I can have it and share it with other students.
공유할 수 있죠
That would be good.
그럼 좋죠
All right.
좋아요
So the next last for this lab is going to be okay.
이 실험실의 마지막은 괜찮을 거예요
Let's take the company brochure generator we made last time and put a user interface around that.
지난번에 만든 회사 브로슈어 생성기를 가져다 사용자 인터페이스를 적용해 보죠.
Wouldn't that be awesome.
그럼 정말 멋지겠죠?
Uh, so now that you know, as I say, it's going to be really, really simple.
이제 아셨으니 말씀드렸듯이 아주 간단할 거예요
So I've decided I'm going with the earlier version of the brochure.
그래서 전 그 책자의 초기 버전을 선택했어요
We're just going to use a, we're going to use just the landing page only.
랜딩 페이지만 사용할 거예요
We're not going to do the, the two step process where we collect all the links, because that's maybe
모든 링크를 모으는 2단계 프로세스는 하지 않겠습니다 지금 필요한 것보다
more involved than we need right now.
더 복잡할 수 있으니까요
Um, we're just going to have a simpler version of the website class that has URL, title and text,
URL과 제목, 텍스트를 가진 웹사이트 클래스의 간단한 버전을 보여드릴게요 어떻게
and you'll remember how it works.
작동하는지 기억하실 거예요
We use the requests package, and we use the wonderful Beautifulsoup to parse to strip out things we
요청 패키지를 사용하고 뷰티풀 get을 이용해 관심 없는
don't care about and to get the text.
걸 걸러내고 텍스트를 얻죠
And there is a little getcontext helper to give us sort of getcontents helper to give us the page title
getcontext 도우미가 있어요 일종의 getcontent 도우미로 페이지 제목과
and body of the page.
본문을 제공하죠
So that's our helper class.
도우미 수업은 여기까지고요
Remember to run it.
실행하는 거 잊지 마요
System prompt.
시스템 프롬프트예요
You're in a system that analyzes the contents of a company website landing page and creates a short
회사 웹사이트의 내용을 분석하고 랜딩 페이지에 짧은 답변을 작성하는
brochure respond.
시스템에 있죠
In markdown there is a system prompt.
마크다운에는 시스템 프롬프트가 있어요
So here is a stream brochure function that takes a company name, a URL and a model.
스트림 브로슈어 함수가 있어요 회사 이름, URL 그리고 모델을 취하죠
Uh, and it's going to say please generate a company brochure for company name.
회사명을 위한 회사 안내 책자를 생성해 달라고 하네요
Here is their landing page.
이게 랜딩 페이지예요
And then we'll use our website helper class here to read in that URL and get the contents.
그런 다음 웹사이트 도우미 클래스를 이용해 해당 URL을 읽고 내용을 get 하죠
So this is all making sense.
이제 이해가 되네요
We're just going to to get the contents of the website.
웹 사이트의 내용을 get 할 거예요
We're going to turn that into a prompt.
그걸 프롬프트로 바꿀게요
And then if it's GPT we're going to stream from GPT.
GPT라면 GPT에서 스트림할 거예요
If it's Claude, we're going to stream from Claude.
클로드면 클로드에서 물을 퍼내야죠
Um, otherwise we'll raise an error and we will then make this a generator and yield the results chunk
안 그러면 에러가 발생해서 발전기를 만들게 되고 결과물이 한 덩어리씩 나올
by chunk.
거예요
Uh, I realize it's a bit bit misleading to call this chunk because it's in fact not actually chunk
비트라고 부르는 게 오해의 소지가 있는 것 같아요 사실 비트 한 덩어리씩이 아니거든요
It's it's the full amount.
총액이에요
So you might want to rename that something that's, uh, a better reflection of what this this is.
이름을 바꾸는 게 좋겠어요 이 상황을 더 잘 반영하는 이름으로요
But you get the idea.
Get you, I'm get you, I'm get you, I'm get it, I'm it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get it, I'm get'm get, I'm get'm get, I'm get.
It should do the trick.
이거면 될 거예요
Uh, so wouldn't it be nice?
그럼 좋지 않을까요?
I'm going to stop saying that because it's going to get old.
Get it이라고 하면 질릴 테니 그만할게요
But it is nice.
하지만 좋아요
It is as simple as now just replacing the function with stream brochure.
함수를 스트림 브로슈어로 대체하는 것만큼 간단해요
And you can see here the inputs.
여기 입력값이 보이시죠
We of course have these three inputs.
물론 세 가지 입력값이 있죠
Now we have a company name.
회사 이름이 생겼네요
We have a landing page URL.
랜딩 페이지 URL이 있어요
And then we can pick the model.
그런 다음 모델을 고르죠
And let's give that a whirl.
한번 해 보죠
Uh here we go.
여기 있네요
Running locally.
현지에서 운영되죠
Bring it up so we can say company name hugging face.
회사명 포옹 얼굴이라고 할 수 있게 띄워 주세요
Landing page URL we can say.
랜딩 페이지 URL도 말할 수 있죠
And we'll just do a.
이렇게 하죠
Hugging s.co and select model.
안아주기요 co와 select 모델을 선택하세요
We will ask GPT to be first add it and then just press submit.
GPT에 먼저 추가하고 제출을 누르라고 요청할 거예요
And here it goes.
이제 시작이네요
Here is our company brochure for Huggingface streaming back in markdown based on our web scrape.
이건 회사 안내 책자예요 헐깅페이스 스트리밍을 마크다운으로 하는 거죠 웹 스크래프를 기반으로요
It's all there.
다 있어요
It's even got links down at the bottom for different things.
심지어 아래쪽에 다양한 용도의 링크가 있어요
Uh, and yeah, that link looks like that is correct.
네, 링크가 맞는 것 같네요
That's going to work.
이거면 되겠어요
Some of these links look like they're not going to work because of, uh, how it's been generated.
몇몇 링크들은 작동하지 않을 것 같습니다 생성된 방식 때문에요
But still, that's a pretty impressive web page, I've got to say, an impressive brochure.
그래도 웹페이지는 정말 인상적이에요 브로슈어도 인상적이고요
I mean, I love it.
정말 좋아요
Let's see what Claude does with this Claude haiku.
클로드가 클로드 하이쿠로 뭘 하는지 보죠
Of course.
물론이죠
So it's, uh, a slimmer model, but it's perfectly acceptable.
좀 더 날씬하지만 이 정도면 괜찮아요
Let's build the future of AI together.
함께 인공지능의 미래를 만들어 나가요
Uh, very nice brochure there from haiku.
하이쿠 책자가 아주 좋네요
Uh, and there we go.
이제 됐어요
I'm.
네
I'm blown away every time I use gradio by how simple it is, how effective it is.
그러디오를 쓸 때마다 정말 놀라워요 얼마나 단순하고 효과적인지 말이에요
We've just built a user interface around our brochure where you can pick between different models and
책자 주위에 사용자 인터페이스를 구축했어요 다른 모델 사이에서 고를 수
let's face it, it was easy.
있죠 인정합시다, 쉬웠어요
So the to dos for you, the ways you can make this better are there are so many.
이 상황을 개선할 방법은 아주 많아요
You could, as I say, add Gemini not only to the earlier example, but to this one as well.
앞서 언급한 제미니를 추가할 수도 있고 이 예제에도 추가할 수 있어요
Another idea is you could add in another selection, another drop down where you can pick the the style,
다른 아이디어는 다른 드롭다운을 추가하는 거예요 스타일이나 톤을 고를 수 있는 드롭다운요
the tone you remember last time, how we could easily change the system prompt so that the brochure
시스템 프롬프트도 쉽게 바꿀 수 있죠 브로슈어가 익살스럽고
was in a humorous, jokey, jovial tone.
농담조로 유쾌하게요
Well, why don't you set it so you can pick from that drop down, choose a different tone, and then
저 드롭다운에서 고를 수 있도록 설정해 볼까요? 다른 톤을 선택하면
it will generate a company brochure using that tone.
그 톤을 이용해 회사 브로슈어를 생성하죠
Uh, it's actually super easy to do that.
사실 엄청 쉬워요
So give it a try.
그러니 한번 해보세요
Do that.
그렇게 해요
And you'll have really beefed up this application to be something that that is increasingly high in
이 응용 프로그램을 강화해 기능성이 점점 더 높아지게 될
functionality.
거예요
So I hope you have fun doing that.
즐거운 시간 보내시길 바라요
Check in the code afterwards.
나중에 코드를 확인하세요
So I get to see it.
Get it, get it. 보여주세요
And I will see you in the next lecture for the wrap up.
그럼 다음 강의에서 마무리하도록 하죠